# Allysson Matheus dos Santos

Software Developer

# Profile

I am a software developer with over three years of experience, working in several high standard systems performing analysis, improvements, developing new features and maintenance, dealing with multiple stakeholders from technical and non-technical backgrounds to ensure the product's quality and continuous delivery.

# **Employment History**

# Systems Analyst at CEABS Serviços, Curitiba

September 2018 - Present

In this role I am responsible for analysing, maintaining, improving and developing new features for APIs RESTful, web and console applications and WCF services. I have been working mainly with C#, .NET Framework, .NET Core, SQL Server, Entity Framework, MySQL, Redshift, Elasticsearch, Solr, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, TFS, GIT, Docker, AWS, Azure. Others tools used in order to perform tasks are TopDesk, TeamWork, Jira and Confluence.

### Software Developer at Rentcars.com, Curitiba

May 2017 - September 2018

My responsibilities included improving, maintaining and developing features for web applications and the RESTful API. My major role was analyzing and integrating SOAP and RESTful web services for new partners. I worked mainly with PHP 5.6, Codelgniter 3, Symfony, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Gulp, MemCache, Npm, Node.JS, Cron jobs, Doctrine ORM, MySQL, Solr. In order to perform fast tests for new web service integrations, we developed automated tests using Java 8 with Selenium. For task management, we used the Scrum methodology and Git for version control with repositories from GitHub and GitLab.

## Junior Programmer at Fator Consult, Curitiba

January 2016 - April 2017

I developed new features and layouts for an ERP project for managing vendors and sales. The technologies used were C#, .NET MVC 4, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, iQuery, Angular 1, Entity Framework and SQL Server.

I was responsible for the development of an admin panel and native apps Android and iOS for a touristic project. The technologies used to build the panel were PHP 5.6, Laravel 5.2, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Eloquent ORM and MySQL. The Android app was developed in Java using libraries such as Retrofit2, Picasso, Jackson, among others. The iOS app was made in Swift 3.0 with Alamofire and other libraries.

### Education

Software Architecture of Distributed Systems, Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais, Curitiba

March 2019 - Present

Computer Systems Analysis, Tuiuti University of Paraná, Curitiba

July 2015 - December 2017

#### Details

+55 041 99660-2531 allysson.lp@gmail.com

#### Links

LinkedIn GitHub Website

#### Skills

C#.NET

**Entity Framework** 

SQL Server

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript

Git

PHP

MySQL

React.js

**AWS** 

Azure DevOps

### Languages

Brazilian Portuguese Native

English

Full professiona proficiency

# Allysson Matheus dos Santos

Desenvolvedor de Software

## Perfil

Sou um desenvolvedor de software com mais de três anos de experiência, trabalhei em diversos sistemas de alto padrão realizando análise, implementações de novas funcionalidades, melhorias e manutenção, interagindo com várias pessoas técnicas e não técnicas, a fim de garantir a qualidade e entrega contínua do produto.

# **Experiências Profissionais**

#### Analista de Sistemas na CEABS Serviços, Curitiba

Setembro 2018 - Presente

Minhas responsabilidades incluem manutenção, melhorias, análise e desenvolvimento de novas funcionalidades das aplicações web, aplicações de console, APIs RESTful e serviços WCF. Dentre as principais tecnologias utilizadas estão C#, .NET Framework, .NET Core, SQL Server, Entity Framework, MySQL, Redshift, Elasticsearch, Solr, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, TFS, GIT, Docker, AWS, Azure. Outras ferramentas utilizadas são TopDesk, TeamWork, Jira e Confluence.

#### Desenvolvedor de Software na Rentcars.com, Curitiba

Maio 2017 - Setembro 2018

Atuei no desenvolvimento de novas funcionalidades, melhorias, e manutenção das aplicações web e API RESTful. Minhas atribuições incluíam analisar e integrar web services SOAP e RESTful de novos parceiros. Dentre as tecnologias utilizadas estão o PHP 5.6, Codelgniter 3, Symfony, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Gulp, MemCache, Npm, NodeJS, Cronjobs, Doctrine ORM, MySQL, Solr. Também atuei em projetos para automatizar os testes de novas integrações, utilizando Java 8 com Selenium. Trabalhei com a metodologia Scrum para definições de tarefas e para o versionamento de código utilizávamos o Git, com repositórios do GitHub e GitLab.

## Programador Júnior na Fator Consult, Curitiba

Janeiro 2016 - Abril 2017

Desenvolvimento de funcionalidades e interfaces gráficas de um projeto para gestão de vendedores e vendas no qual foram utilizadas as tecnologias: C#, .NET MVC 4, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ¡Query, Angular 1, Entity ORM e SQLServer.

Fui responsável pelo desenvolvimento de um painel administrativo e aplicações nativas Android e iOS de um projeto turístico. Na construção do painel administrativo foram utilizadas as tecnologias: PHP 5.6, Laravel 5.2, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Eloquent ORM e MySQL. A aplicação para Android foi desenvolvida em Java, junto às bibliotecas: Retrofit2, Picasso e Jackson. E para o desenvolvimento iOS foi utilizado Swift 3.0 e a biblioteca Alamofire.

# **≈** Educação

Arquitetura de Software Distribuído, Pontifícia Universidade Católica de Minas Gerais, Curitiba

Março 2019 - Presente

Análise e Desenvolvimento de Sistemas, Universidade Tuiuti do Paraná, Curitiba

Julho 2015 - Dezembro 2017

#### Detalhes

+55 041 99660-2531 allysson.lp@gmail.com

#### Links

LinkedIn GitHub Website

#### Habilidades

C#.NET

**Entity Framework** 

SQL Server

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript

Git

PHP

MySQL

React.is

**AWS** 

Azure DevOps

#### Línguas

Português do Brasil Nativo

Inglês Nível avançado